《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
NARRATOR: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
我们没能把她救过来
We lost her.
我们尽了全力 可她还是死了
We did the best we could, but she's dead. And that's all there is to it.
从现在起 就我们两个了 我们说好了的 不管发生什么
It's you and me from now on, no matter what. Just like we agreed.
我就是忘不了我们的女儿
I just can't get her out of my head, our little girl.
她真漂亮
She's so beautiful.
你要知道 玛雅 此次收养必须对外保密
You understand, Maya, that this adoption requires absolute secrecy.
我保证
You have my word.
我只是离开卡拉狄加 不是离开你
I'm leaving Galactica, not you.
我不知道我们会怎样
I don't know how we can.
我也是 不过我会努力的
I don't either, but I know I'm gonna try
如果你也是
if you will.
我是卡维儿修士
I'm Brother Cavil.
听说你要求宗教咨询
I understand you've asked for religious counseling.
让我们谈谈到底发生了什么
Let's talk about what happened.
上士?
Chief?
啊
Ah!
我不知道我怎么会对凯丽做出这样的事
TYROL: I don't understand how I could do that to Cally.
你认为自己是赛昂人
BROTHER CAVIL: You think you're a Cylon.
我不是赛昂人
I am not a Cylon.
你当然不是
Well, of course you're not,
可这不就是你害怕的么?
but that's what you're afraid of, isn't it?
我们也有个赛昂囚犯
CAIN: We have our own Cylon prisoner.
她显然受过虐待和折磨
NO. 6: She's obviously been abused, tortured.
我知道一个你可以待的地方 在那你会安全的
I know a place where you can stay, where you will be safe.
我可以照看你
Where I can look after you...
副总统波尔塔博士以此作为他诚意的证明
Vice President Baltar offered the contents of this case as proof of his sincerity
一个核弹?
GINA: A nuclear bomb?
我想除了宣布自己现在
I'm afraid that I have no alternative
正式参加总统竞选外 别无选择了
but to announce that I am, as of now, a candidate for the presidency.
现在最关键的是
What should be important to you, personally,
罗丝琳在民调中领先三点
is that Roslin's up three points in the polls.
我这探测到一个很大的星体
SKULLS: Hey, I'm picking up a large planetary body.
你猜什么?
Hey, you know what this is?
这里可以住人
It's habitable.
我们可能找到了一个适合人类栖息的星球
We may have just found a world that can support human life.
我们需要一些可以让我们
ZAREK: We needed an issue,
区别于罗丝林的东西
something to set us apart from Roslin.
这就是了
This is it.
永远定居在这颗星上
Permanent settlement on this planet.
怎么你这么晚才来?
What took you so long?
我们带了陆战队和猛禽机
We got Marines and Raptors.
我们要把你们弄出去
We're gonna get you and your people out of here, okay?
敌袭
Incoming!
快走
MARINE: Go! Go! Go!
没有退路了
MAN: There's no way out!
快走
Go! Move!
起来 继续前进
WOMAN: Get up and get going.
我们被围攻了
They've got us zeroed in.
这样下去 我们都会被干掉
If we stay here, they're gonna chew us up!
我们撤到那个山头去
All right, we've got to fall back. Position up this hill. Let's go!
行动    出发
Let's move, people! MARINE 1: Let's go! Let's go!
出发
MARINE 2: Let's go! Let's go!
你的下巴已经固定好了
The jaw's set nicely. You're done here.
你可以回去工作了
I'm kicking you out of here and sending you back to work.
像这样?
Work? Like this?
你都可以吵嘴了
You gotta love a woman who can complain even with her jaw wired shut.
你有访客了
You got a visitor.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我做的实在是
What I did was
不可饶恕
unforgivable,
不可宽恕
inexcusable.
我来这...
I didn't come here to...
我原谅你了
I forgive you.
不 凯丽
No, Cally, no.
那不是你 我知道的
It wasn't you. I know that.
那不是你
It wasn't you.
那是我
It was me.
我当时根本不知道自己在做什么
I may have been out of my mind and not know where I was...
可那是我
Doing or anything, but it was me.
你很痛苦
You're in pain.
我知道你一直都很痛苦
I know you've been in pain for a really long time.
不用替我找借口
Don't feel sorry for me.
我很在乎你 一直都很在乎你
I care about you. I always have.
将来也是
I always will.
前进
BOOMER: Move! Come on!
快走    起来
Let's go! Let's go! MARINE: Come on, get up!
都起来
Get them up! Get them up!
这边
This way!
快走 那边
HELO: Let's go! Get in there! Let's go!
走啊
Let's go! Let's go!
快 来这边
STARBUCK: Come on, get in here!
带他去那边 快
HELO: Get him up there! Get him up there, now!
莎伦 拿枪
Sharon, take the gun!
弹药
Ammo!
我们被困住了
STARBUCK: They've got us boxed in here really good!
联系不上猛禽机
Can't reach the Raptors.
赛昂人干扰了无线电
The Cylons have jammed the freqs.
靠
MARINE: Frak!
他们后撤了?
Are they still out there?
自己小心
Watch yourself.
好像是撤了
STARBUCK: Yeah, they're holding back, though.
可为什么呢?
Yeah, but why?
他们守在那 等非杀伤性武器运到
They're holding position, sending for non-lethal weapons.
他们想抓几个人去审问
They want some prisoners for interrogation.
把其他人扔到农场里
The rest they're gonna send to the farm.
我可不愿意被弄到弄场里
STARBUCK: I'm not going back to one of those farms.
可你没得选 我们都一样
Yeah, well, you don't have any choice. None of us will.
他们会扔几颗致晕弹进来  等我们醒过了就不在这了
They're gonna lob some gas in here and then we'll all wake up somewhere else.
该死
Damn.
你准备怎么办?
So what you want to do here?
坐在这等 看看她是否说中
Sit it out. Wait and see if she's right.
如果是这么回事  就按我们说好的办
If she is, then you and me, we've gotta have an agreement.
说好的什么?
An agreement?
我可不想到什么农场去
I'm not going back to one of those farms, Sam. I'm not.
如果她说对了
So if she's right
他们真的扔致晕弹
and they throw gas in here,
我们两就一块自杀
you do me, I do you.
你说什么?
What are you talking about?
这就是我的意思 知道了?
This is what I'm talking about, okay?
我懂了
Yeah, okay.
好
Okay.
今天下午又下降了两点 听说了他在社会政策上的想法
Down two more points, and this after hearing his notions of social policy.
更不要提他那意想的什么保障政策
Not to mention his wishful thinking that he's calling security policy.
民众难道真的如此愚蠢?
Are people really gonna be that stupid?
如此短视?
Are they really gonna be that shortsighted?
这是民众唯一关心的东西
TORY: He's got the only issue people care about.
哦 我知道 那个星球
Oh, I know. The planet.
大家关心的就是那个鬼星球
That's all anybody wants to talk about is a frakking planet.
刚才那些话真抱歉
Excuse my... My language, Tory. I'm sorry.
我知道在这星球定居的话题会在民众间掀起滔天巨浪
I know in my gut that settling on this planet's gonna mean disaster
但我不会仅为赢得选举就同意的
for humanity, and I will not say otherwise just to win an election.
如你所想 总统女士
As you wish, Madam President.
看来我应该开始把办公室里的东西整理打包了
So, I guess I should start packing up my office
除非你还有什么好的方案
unless you have some super-secret back-up plan for victory in your pocket.
预备的方案是有的
There's always a back-up plan for victory.
牧师就要到了
Just in time for the priest.
好的 让他进来
Oh, good. Send him in.
已经18个小时
18 hours.
他们在那一定玩得很开心
They're taking their good, sweet time out there.
到了晚上他们可能选任何时候攻击我们
They could've overrun us at any point during the night.
他们一定在等什么
They're up to something.
那你又在等什么?
What are we up to?
你那有军事学养的脑袋里有何妙想?
Got any brilliant ideas in that military brain of yours?
我们就这样保持现状
We do the same thing we always do,
直到扛不住为止
fight them till we can't.
你怎么说?
HELO: What do you think?
组一个侦察小队
Let's get a recon crew together.
到那去探探
Scout the area.
看看到底发生了什么
Figure out what's going on out there.
安全
Clear.
他们都撤走了
They're gone.
他们离开了
They just left.
感谢神
Thank the gods.
这是个奇迹
It's a miracle.
让我们祈祷
Let us pray.
科波之神 我们相信你的仁慈和正直
Lords of Kobol, we trust in your benevolence and praise your righteousness.
请启迪民众的智慧
Give the people of this fleet the wisdom to see the goodness
让大家了解您仆人罗丝琳的善良和力量
and the strength of your servant, Laura Roslin.
阿门
Amen.
上将?
Admiral?
总统女士
Madam President...
上将不在
The Admiral's not here.
我想就我们两个谈谈
This is my meeting.
没有记者的干扰
I wanted us to talk privately, without the press getting wind of it.
请坐
Please have a seat.
你一定有些很有意思的话要说
Well, you must have something very interesting to say to resort to such
当然也免不了带些老套的诡计
pedestrian methods of deception.
永久定居的问题
The question of permanent settlement
是自我们被攻击以来最重要的事
may well be the most important issue we face since the attack.
我同意    好
I agree. Good.
在做最终决定以前此事应该被慎重地考虑
The question should be carefully studied before making the final decision.
在选举中就做决定实在太过仓促
And the middle of an election campaign is hardly the time for careful study.
因此我提议
Therefore, I propose a truce.
我们共同发表一项申明
You and I will issue a joint statement
将定居的问题拖到选举以后再定夺
declaring that the question be tabled till after this election.
不论谁当选都得保证
We will both pledge that regardless of who is elected,
慎思熟虑后 我们才决定是否要定居
the decision will be made only after careful deliberation
必须考虑所有的因素
involving all elements of the public,
并征询军事专家和十二殖民星代表的意见
and after consultation with the military and the Quorum of Twelve.
博士
Doctor,
我知道我们有个人分歧
I know we've had our disagreements,
可这个问题高过我们的分歧
but this issue transcends personal disagreement
也凌驾于政治之上
as well as politics.
我请求你发扬爱国精神
I am appealing here to your sense of patriotism.
我的爱国心始终如一
Let me tell you, my sense of patriotism is doing just fine.
谢谢你的关心
Thank you very much for asking.
我将把这个舰队领向新世界
I see it as my patriotic duty
作为自己的爱国之举
to lead this fleet to a new world.
那个世界一定会是一个新的卡布里卡
That new world is unquestionably New Caprica.
谢了 总统女士
But thank you, Madam President,
您刚刚向我显示了
for demonstrating to me
你的竞选活动是多么令人绝望
just how desperate your campaign for reelection has become.
在卡布里卡被攻击前 你有和一个金发女子在一起
Were you with a blonde woman on Caprica just prior to the attack?
你说什么?
What?
她知道了
She knows.
你在我们被攻击前
Were you
有没有和一个
with a tall, blonde woman
高个金发女子
in the Riverwalk section of Caprica City,
在卡布里卡的莱福华克区?
just prior to the attack?
她看穿你了
She can see right through you.
快离开
Get out of here now.
我看你开始不择手段了
You'll resort to anything at this stage, won't you?
我在卡布里卡的事情 还有我和谁在一起
I'm afraid my affairs on Caprica, and who I chose to consort with,
都和你一点不相干
are none of your business.
另外 是我救了你的命
You know, I saved your life.
但我不会在政治上帮你的
I won't save your political career.
我们不会定居在那的
We are not moving down to that planet.
如果波尔塔赢得选举
If Baltar wins the election...
他不可能会赢
Baltar won't win the goddamn election...
如果他赢了呢?
If he does, then what?
难道我们就待在这船上等着这里烂掉?
We're gonna just sit on this ship and rot
而其他人都开始新生活
while everyone else gets to start a new life?
艾伦 保护这舰队是我的职责
Ellen, my job is to protect the fleet from the Cylons,
也是我正在做的
and that's exactly what I'll be doing.
如果你要下到那去  那你就自己去定居吧
If you want to move down there, go ahead, be my guest.
到下面混在男人堆里
Go down and cat around with all the men,
就像你昔日里那样
have yourself a good old time.
索尔 我想让你...
Saul, I want you.
我是副指挥官
XO.
开什么玩笑
You got to be kidding me.
我马上下来
I'll be right down.
星芭儿回来了
Starbuck's back.
我得下去了
I gotta get down there.
瞧那是谁来着?
WOMAN: Put him in here!
我还以为你回不来了
Hey, hey, guys, take it easy with it. Come on.
我好好的吧?
Am I good or what?
没人和她一起了
There's gonna be no living with her now.
很高兴见到到 欢迎归队
It's good to see you. Welcome back.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, sir.
我带回了些朋友
I brought some friends with me.
瞧见了
I see.
对了
Right, right. Um...
这
This is, um...
这是赛穆…
Wow. This is Samuel T. Anders of...
我知道他
I know who he is.
很高兴见到你 先生
Damn good to meet you, sir.
卡布里卡的巴克球队的?    是的
Caprica Buccaneers. That's right.
一个球员
A hell of a player.
我是皮康豹队的支持者
Picon Panther fan myself.
我们也以击败他们为荣
Well, we enjoy beating them, too.
欢迎登舰    谢谢
It's good to have you aboard. Thank you.
我有个好消息
I have news. Good news, actually.
赛隆人的占领结束了
The Cylon occupation is over.
他们离开了
They left. They're gone.
你说什么?
What are you talking about?
是真的
BROTHER CAVIL 2: It's true.
赛隆人离开了殖民星
The Cylons have left the Colonies.
他们去了别处
They're headed for greener pastures.
卫兵
Security!
怎么了
What the hell?
紧急状态
Code Blue!
他是赛隆人
He's a Cylon.
退后 士官长 我们知道了
Back off, Chief. We've got him.
还真尴尬
Well, this is an awkward moment.
是的 我是个赛隆人
Yes, he's right. I'm a Cylon.
我要捎个口信
And I have a message.
我要见你们的领导人
So, take me to your leader.
把他关起来
Take him to the brig.
把那东西也关起来
Take that to the brig, too.
上将她不知情
HELO: What? Admiral, she didn't know...
闭嘴
Don't even start.
她肯定知道的
Of course she knew.
欢迎登舰
Welcome to Galactica.
为什么你当初不告诉我?
Why the frak didn't you say anything?
我不知道 或许是不想告诉你…
I don't know. Maybe I didn't want to.
可能是我想让他上来  把这船炸掉
Or maybe I wanted him to come here and blow up the whole ship.
这不就是你想要得答案?
Is that what you're looking for?
嗯
Hmm?
你不是认真的
You don't mean that.
莎伦 我们总算得到了上将一点点信任
Sharon, we'd finally got the Admiral to start trusting us.
一点点
Finally.
可现在呢?
And what?
他们杀了我的孩子
They killed my baby.
你以为我还会在乎你或是我们的事?
You think I care about you or us
或是什么上将的信任?
or whether the Admiral trusts me anymore?
嗨
Hey!
莎伦 我爱你
Sharon, I love you!
我不会轻易放弃的 绝不
And I'm not giving up this frakking easy! Not after everything!
准备好了？  好
Are you ready? All right.
啊哈
Aah!
不 不
No, no, no, no, no.
是 是
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
听着 你不用灌我
Hey, hey, hey, listen, you don't have to get me drunk.
我会和你一起睡的
I will sleep with you, okay?
我想我还欠着你呢
I figure I owed you one, what with you saving me and all.
你现在好淫荡    闭嘴
Little slut. Shut up.
你想玩硬的啦    对
Now you're gonna play hard to get. Yeah.
我的英雄
My hero.
天啊 这些天谁都能来这了
Gods, I guess they'll let anybody in here these days.
嗨
Hey.
你好
Hi.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
看看我的男人
Do you want to meet my man?
你的男人?
Your man? Hmm.
我的私人财产
My personal property.
对吧 山米
Right, Sammy?
不要叫我山米
Don't call me Sammy.
哦
Oh!
成为我私人财产的感觉如何
How does it feel to be my personal property?
对对对
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
在你回答前
And before you answer.
他喜欢这样
He loves it.
我赌是的 我是李
I bet he does. I'm Lee, by the way.
塞缪尔  抱歉
Hey, Samuel. I'm sorry.
我听说了你的很多事情
I've heard a lot about you.
来一杯?
Pleasure. A shot?
当然
Sure, why not.
李 你何时也找个女孩?
Lee, when are you gonna get yourself a girl?
我很好 谢了
I'm doing fine, thank you.
你还没搞定小杜 对不?
You're not still frakking Dualla, are you?
谢谢
Thanks a lot.
我不喜欢说教
I'm not one to like, you know, lecture or anything
我只是及时行乐
'cause I'll do just about anything to get into the pants
特别是和胸大无脑的女人
of some hot, little young thing.
嗨！
Hey!
你就是这么看我的?
Is that all I am to you?
是的 你喜欢这样
Yes, but you love it.
没错 我不介意做做善事
That's right. I don't mind doing charity work.
你就是胸大无脑的女人  而你也知道
You are a hot, little thing, but you know that.
多谢了
Thank you.
他去哪了
Where did he go?
我只是来捎个口信
I'm here to deliver a message.
在此之后 随便你把我如何 我不在乎
After that, you can do whatever you want with me. I don't care.
你能告诉我发生了什么吗?
Would you mind telling me what's going on?
我才不是什么赛昂人呢
I'm not a frakking Cylon. I'm not...
哦
Oh. Well.
好吧
Okay, then.
兄弟 抱歉我害了你
Sorry to bust up your day, Brother,
我们修改了计划
but there's been a change of plans.
我们现在认为  占领殖民星是一个错误
It's been decided that the occupation of the Colonies was an error.
我早就说过那是错的
I could have told them that.
坏想法 逻辑混乱
Bad thinking, faulty logic.
一开始就错了
Our first major error of judgment.
吃一堑长一智
Well, live and learn. But the war heroes
我们的英雄已经改变了立场
have managed to swing opinion over to their side.
什么英雄?
What heroes?
一个六号和一个八号 八号就是莎伦
A Six and an Eight. One of the Eights you know as Sharon Valerii.
她们说话很有分量
Their voices carry a lot of weight,
因此当他们说到我们犯的错 我们的自我堕落
so when they started talking about our mistakes and our corruption
以及我们需要一个新的开始
and our need for a new beginning,
我们其他人都同意了
the rest of us listened to them.
你看 我们和你们不同
You see, we're not like you.
我们愿意承认错误  我们不惧怕改变
We can admit our mistakes, and we're not afraid of change.
所以你们丢下了殖民星
So you abandoned the Colonies,
留下满目疮痍的  核武器污染过的土地
leaving behind a devastated, nuclear wasteland.
我们还该感恩喽?
And we're supposed to be grateful?
追着你们舰队也是一个错误
Our pursuit of this fleet of yours was another error.
那两个错误
That's two, for anyone who's keeping score.
导致了一个结果
Both errors led to the same result.
我们变成原先自己痛恨的样子
We became what we beheld.
我们变得和你们一样了
We became you.
阿门
Amen.
人们必须接纳自身
People should be true to who and what they are.
如果我们是机器
We're machines.
我们就得像个机器
We should be true to that.
成为宇宙中最好的机器
Be the best machines the universe has ever seen.
可我们总忘不了是人类创造了我们
But we got it into our heads that we were the children of humanity.
我们没有…
So, instead of pursuing our own destiny
好好探询自己的路
of trying to find our own path to enlightenment,
而是抢了你们的
we hijacked yours.
兄弟 你说吧
You said it, Brother.
我来的目的很简单
My mission here is simple.
告诉你们我们放过你们了
I'm to tell you that you've been given a reprieve.
赛隆人和人类现在开始要分道而行
Cylon and man will now go their separate ways.
停止互相残杀
No harm done.
不互相残杀?
No harm?
你们差点把我们灭了族
You completely annihilated our race
毁了我们的文明
and destroyed our civilization.
又开始指责了
Now, if you're gonna start pointing fingers...
你们赛隆人要到哪去? 回到自己的家园?
Where did the Cylons go? Back to their home world?
我现在不便透露
Well, I'd rather not say just now.
只能告诉你我们有了其他计划
Let's just say we have other plans.
看来是你们的真神又降下了新的旨意
New marching orders by your one true god?
根本就没有什么神祗
There is no god.
超自然的神学只是些很原始的论调
Supernatural divinities are the primitive's answer
为了解释为什么太阳升起和落下
for why the sun goes down at night.
我们早就讨论了很久了
At least that's what we've been telling the others for years.
既不能证实 也不能证否
We can't really prove it one way or the other, of course.
我知道怎么来证明
You know a way to prove it?
把他们扔出减压舱   让他们看看是否有赛昂人的真神
Throw them both out the airlock. Let them see if there really is a Cylon god.
亚得里亚的选票?
Ballots from the Adriatic. D?
对    这边走
Right. This way.
真是激动人心的一天
MCMANUS:It has been an exciting day.
整个选举高潮迭起
The election has been a real rollercoaster ride.
现在是投票结束后五小时
The polls now have been closed for about five hours,
记票结果的最新消息不断传来
results have come in, and it's been a see-saw battle,
候选人的票数依旧旗鼓相当
back and forth between the presidential candidates.
整晚都如我们所期待的那样
So, all night long, as we of course suspected it would be.
我们仍然在等待来自统计室内
We're still waiting for a few more numbers to come in now,
最新的数字
from the counting room of Galactica,
有些人可能已经知道了
which, I must tell you, as some of you may know,
昨天发生了一些争议
was the source of a bit of a controversy yesterday.
竞选顾问扎克就对军方
Councilman Zarek had filed a formal complaint
提出了抗议
against the use of military...
军方介入了选举过程
The military involvement in the election process.
最后双方达成了妥协
Now, it's just reached... A compromise was just reached
由卡拉狄加
late yesterday, allowing Galactica
提供选举安全保障
to provide security for the balloting,
而整个记票过程会有
as well as civilians to oversee
民众代表全程监督
and then to monitor the situation.
就在现在我们又收到新的消息
Yes, okay. Now we have some more votes coming in here.
统计还没结束 不过波尔塔博士又获得了6286票
Still not done, but what we have so far is 6,282 more votes for Baltar,
这样他总计
which puts his total now to
就有了21569票
21,569.
这准确吗?
Is that... Is that correct?
而罗丝琳
And we also have Roslin.
她的总票数是17754
Her total now is at 17,754.
就是说又多了2981票
We've had 2,981 more votes come in for Roslin at this time.
以上是当下的形势
So that is how things are looking at this point.
我们会继续追踪选举的情况
We'll continue to bring you up-to-the-minute coverage as the count progresses.
是我
Yeah, it's me.
通讯线路加密了吗?
Is this a secure line?
好的
Okay.
现在还剩5艘船的票没记
There are only five ships left to report in.
要干就趁现在
We need to move now.
我会搞定的
I'll take care of it.
中尉
Lieutenant.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
这是从赛芬来的吗?
Are those the ballots from the Zephyr?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
从这里开始归我们管了
All right, we'll take it from here.
我们接到的命令是送到里面
We were told to take these to the ballot room, sir.
记票早开始了 我们接管了
Counting has already begun. We'll take it from here.
那边
GAETA: Right there, please.
最后一个了
Last one.
现在又有了新形势
We have some more results that have come in here now.
那么…
And, uh...
罗丝琳又得到了8593票
Wow, okay. 8,593 for Roslin,
这下她领先了
now, which puts her over the top.
罗丝琳共得了24265票
That's 24,265 for Laura Roslin.
准确吗
Is that correct?
而盖尤斯.波尔塔博士是22366票
And 22,366 for Gaius Baltar.
我们得再确认一下 这样的话她就领先了
We're gonna check these again because that has put her over the top.
她成功了
She... She has done it.
就在几乎不可能的情况下
She has retained the Presidency
她最终连任成功了
in an improbable comeback in the final hours of the campaign.
我们待会会再确认一下选举结果
Again we will, of course, like to check those numbers if we could,
不过罗丝琳确实获胜了
but it appears that Laura Roslin has retained the Presidency
和先前的民调结果不一样
in defiance of the polls, the pundits and the purveyors of gloom and doom.
我还是第一次遇到这样的情况
But I've never seen a political race end like this,
可它就是发生了
but it has just happened.
我是詹姆士 马克马努斯 我们会核准这些数据
I'm James McManus. We'll check those numbers
很快会告诉大家 谢谢
and we'll get back to you very shortly. Thank you.
我经历过很多选举 盖尤斯
I've seen a lot of elections, Gaius.
老实说 其中有些是作了弊的
Most honest, a few fixed.
你总能知道哪些是作了弊的
And you can always tell the fixed ones because they don't make sense.
而这次他们一定是作了弊
And this doesn't make sense.
劳拉 罗丝琳有很多问题
Laura Roslin is many things,
但她没有作弊
but she's not corrupt.
她并非是骗子
And she's not dishonest.
结束了
It's over.
祝贺你 总统女士
Congratulations, Madam President.
谢谢你
Well, thank you.
请你不要误解我的意思
I hope you don't take this the wrong way,
你对此和我一样震惊吗?
but are you as shocked as I am?
我倒是更觉得轻松
I'm relieved.
但听你的语气不像
Well, you don't sound it.
我只是累了而已
I'm just tired.
好长的竞选活动啊
It's been a long campaign.
上校
Colonel?
可以聊一下吗?
May I speak to you for a moment?
怎么了
What's up?
赛芬来的票恐怕记错了
Sir, I'm afraid these ballots from the Zephyr are wrong.
你说什么?
What the hell are you talking about?
波尔塔博士的名字在这里是拼写正确的
Dr. Baltar's name is spelled correctly on these ballots.
但今天早上赛芬联系我时
But this morning the Zephyr called me
说他们的选票印错了
and told me their ballots had a misprint.
波尔塔的名字被拼错了
They misspelled Baltar's first name.
我们没时间重新印
We didn't have time to print new ballots,
我让那的官员直接用印错的选票
so I told them on my authority to go ahead, use them anyway.
波尔塔的名字在这拼写正确
Baltar's name is spelled correctly here.
那这些就不是来自赛芬的票
So they couldn't have come from the Zephyr.
他们在舞弊
They're frauds.
而从赛芬到这的全过程
Now, there's a complete chain of custody
看上去都没问题
from the Zephyr, all the way into this room.
一定是某个环节出现了舞弊
So someone in the chain is either the perpetrator
至少是有…
or at least, a willing ally in...
我知道了
Thanks for bringing this to my attention.
我会处理的
I'll take care of it from here.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
至少应该将此事告知观察员
We should at least notify the civilian observers
以及媒体
and the press that these ballots will...
我说了我会处理的
I said I'll take care of it from here.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
总统女士 你应该庆贺
Madam President, you should celebrate.
你赢得了伟大的胜利
It's a great victory and you've earned it.
抱歉
Excuse me.
上将 我们吃些再谈 谢谢你
Admiral, we'll talk later. Thank you.
阿达玛
Adama.
是 长官 我是盖塔中尉
Yes, sir, this is Lieutenant Gaeta.
长官
Sir,
我本不想说的
I don't know how to say this...
直说无妨
Fast and straight, I'd advise.
好的
Yes, sir.
我想泰上校参加了
Admiral, I believe that Colonel Tigh is involved in a conspiracy
让罗丝琳当选的阴谋
to rig the election for President Roslin.
我找了上校谈话  他承认自己做了假
When I confronted the Colonel, he admitted his guilt.
他承认和你的助手托瑞
He said he acted in collusion with your campaign manager,
共谋了此事
Tory Foster.
他们几天前联络上的
Saul said Tory had contacted him a few days ago.
他这样做是因为他认为波尔塔当选会是一场灾难
He did it because he felt that Baltar as president would be a disaster.
这点我也同意
I said I agree,
但他犯了法
but that what he had done was illegal.
他就要受到审判
A judicial tribunal may have to be convened.
够了
Stop.
是我让托瑞放手干的
I gave Tory the go ahead.
我不知道她的具体计划
I didn't know exactly what she was planning.
我真的不知道泰上校会涉及此事
I certainly didn't know about Colonel Tigh. Oh, my Gods.
但我是知道她打算窜改投票结果的
But I did know that she was planning to fix the vote.
你想在选举中作假来获胜?
You tried to steal an election?
是的
Yes, I did.
而且我被抓住了
And I got caught.
但盖尤斯 波尔塔
But Gaius Baltar
决不能做总统
cannot become President of the Colonies, Bill.
我不能让他做
It cannot happen.
劳拉
Laura,
我也不想让他成为总统
I don't want him as President either, but...
他是赛昂人的同伙
He's working with the Cylons.
在赛昂人进攻卡布里卡之前
I saw him just before the attack on Caprica
我看到他和一个金发高个赛昂女人在一起
with a copy of the tall, blonde Cylon woman.
就是那个指控波尔塔是叛徒的同型赛昂人
The same model who accused Baltar of treason
又从卡布里卡消失了
before disappearing from Galactica.
你在说什么?
What the hell are you saying?
你为什么不早说呢?
Why didn't you say something before this?
因为我在自己上次差点死掉前
Because I didn't remember seeing him with that woman
根本没想起过这事
until I remembered it when I was dying.
我知道这听起来怪怪的 但我说的全是真的
I know how that sounds, but it's real.
科波之路是真的
The same way Kobol is real
雅典娜神殿也是真的
and the Tomb of Athena is real.
到地球的导航图也是真的
And the map to Earth is real.
波尔塔一直在为赛昂人工作
Baltar is working with the Cylons.
就算是真的 你也没证据
Even if that's true, you have no proof.
对 我没有
No, I don't.
我们不能偷取竞选结果
Do we steal the results of a democratic election or not?
这是最终决定
That's the decision.
如果这样做 我们就成罪犯了
Because if we do this, we're criminals.
虽然不会有人告发
Unindicted, maybe,
但犯罪就是犯罪
but criminals just the same.
是的
Yes, we are.
你不能这么做
You won't do it.
我们走的太远了 就此为止吧
We've gone this far, but that's it.
你说什么?
Excuse me?
你试图偷窃竞选结果 你的心已经死了
You try to steal this election, you'll die inside.
就像癌细胞侵占了你的心脏
Likely move your cancer right to your heart.
人们作出了自己的选择
People made their choice.
我们得接受事实
We're gonna have to live with it.
这是错误的选择
It's the wrong choice.
是的
Yes, it is.
好吧 好吧
All right, all right, all right.
那么就这样完了?
So, that's it.
我们就这样放弃了?
We just give it up, just like that.
就选举来说 也许吧
The battle perhaps,
但我们还没丢了这场战争
but not the war.
重要的是我们纠正了错误
Well, the important thing is the error was discovered and corrected.
你现在是总统了 祝贺你
You've been elected President. Congratulations.
非常感谢 上将
Thank you very much, Admiral.
现在说说那个失误吧
Now about this error.
到底是什么样的计算错误
Exactly what kind of a tabulating error
会发生在你的船上
could have occurred on your ship
让几千张投给我的选票
that could have swung several thousand votes away from me
记成投给你所偏爱的罗丝琳的?
in favor of your preferred candidate, Admiral?
等我有空了一定会调查的
As soon as I have the time, there will be an investigation.
我建议你接受胜利
I suggest that you take your victory
就此罢手 博士
and you leave it at that, Doctor.
我想你会发现我是多么宽宏大量
I think you'll find I can be magnanimous in victory, Admiral.
我同时建议你改称我为
And I believe the correct honorific at this time is
总统当选人
Mr. President Elect.
让我们向新卡布里卡进发
Set a course for New Caprica.
跳跃完成 我们已经在新卡布里卡的轨道上了
Jump completed. We are in orbit around New Caprica.
所有的船都到了
We have all ships present and accounted for, sir.
让帕伽索斯号派出登陆队
Send word to the Pegasus to launch their initial ground team onto the surface.
让我们好好看看我们的新家
ADAMA: Let's get a good look at our new home.
求神保佑我们
Gods help us all.
好吧
Well...
由于我的新职位
I think my ability to see you will no doubt be
我职责所在
constrained by the responsibilities,
不能经常见你
the requirements of my new position.
听我说
Listen to me.
我的新职位
My new position.
不过
But obviously, we...
我们还是有机会在一起的
We will have the chance to connect, to get together again
到了新卡布里卡就又可以...
on New Caprica, once...
我不打算去新卡布里卡
I'm not going to New Caprica.
什么
What?
你说什么
What are you talking about?
我不打算去新卡布里卡
I'm not going to New Caprica.
我们都要去去卡布里卡
We're all going to New Caprica.
全部
All of us.
我们所有人
Every last, single one of us.
这是一个在一起的机会
It's our chance to be together.
再次在一起
To be together again.
不
No.
我受不了了
I can't do this anymore.
留下来
Stay.
请举起右手跟我念
If you'll raise your right hand and repeat after me.
我 盖尤斯 波塔尔 现坚定不移
"I, Gaius Baltar, do now avow and affirm. "
接掌科波十二殖民星
"That I take the office of the President
总统一职
"of the 12 Colonies of Kobol
无所保留
"without any moral reservation or mental evasion. "
接掌科波十二殖民星
"That I take the office of President
总统一职
"of the 12 Colonies of Kobol
无所保留
"without any moral reservation or mental evasion. "
我会守护好殖民星宪章
"That I will protect and defend the articles of colonization. "
尽我所能
"With every fiber of my being. "
祝贺你 总统先生
Congratulations, Mr. President.
WOMAN: Congratulations, Mr. President.
祝贺你
MAN: Congratulations.
我以谦卑和感恩之心
BALTAR: I accept the role offered to me by the Colonies
接受殖民地赋予我的职责
with humility and gratitude.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
不 不 等等
No, no, no, wait.
现在
And now,
出于民众的首要期望
because it was the first will of the people,
我现在要宣布我第一个命令
I am going to sign my first executive order,
要求立即在那个将被叫做
requiring to immediately establish settlements
新卡布里卡的星球建立定居点
on the planet we have come to know as New Caprica.
这就是给你们的命令
You have your orders.
我们猜那个弹头是从你的实验室偷的
We suspect the warhead was stolen from your lab,
被一个赛昂间谍带到星云9号
then smuggled aboard Cloud Nine by a Cylon agent.
我想你对茶没兴趣吧 上将
I don't suppose I could interest you in a cup of tea, Admiral?
一杯阿姆布罗西亚酒
A glass of ambrosia, biscuit...
总统先生
Mr. President,
这可能是赛昂攻击计划的第一步
this may be the first step in a coordinated Cylon attack.
我建议将现在的工作重点放到内部安全上来
I suggest our first priority be to focus in on internal security.
不
No.
我不这么想
No, I don't think so.
我们现在的第一要务
Our first priority is to the people.
是让人们能在新卡布里卡上安全定居
See that they are safely established on New Caprica.
那完成之后
Once that's accomplished,
人们就能从这次的悲痛中恢复
we can put this tragedy behind us.
你没好好听我说
You're not listening.
我不需要听了
I don't have to listen.
我是总统
I'm the President.
现在就开始进行定居
The settlement begins and it begins now.
总统先生
GAETA: Mr. President?
波尔塔总统 早上好 先生
President Baltar, good morning, sir.
早上好 先生
Good morning, sir.
哦
Oh.
联合会要求你的答复
Mr. President, the union needs their answer.
联合会
The union.
不是联合会 就是法人代表团
If it's not the union, it's the Quorum.
不是法人代表团 就是人民议会
If it's not the Quorum, it's the people's council.
我们从一场核灾难中生还了 盖塔先生
We survived a nuclear holocaust, Mr. Gaeta,
而民众却在抱怨天气不好
and the people complain about the weather.
不是抱怨天气…
Well, sir, it's hardly the weather...
不管是什么
Well, whatever it is.
自从我当了总统  赛昂人攻击过我们几次?
How many Cylon attacks have there been since I took office?
几次?
How many?
没有过
None, sir.
对 没有 那为何人们还抱怨呢?
None. Precisely. So why do the people complain?
告诉联合会不要再来烦我
Tell the union to get off their fat asses
给我卖力工作
and do some frakking work for a change
要不我就软禁他们的领导
or I'll start rounding up their leaders
甚至把他们关起来
and holding them in detention.
我猜他们不会喜欢的
I doubt they'll like that very much.
我会告诉他们的 总统先生
I'll tell them, Mr. President.
谢谢
Thank you.
早上好
Good morning.
我的药去哪了?
Where's my... Where's my pills?
你可以到地面上去了
ADAMA: I'm telling you to go, okay?
不 一点也不好
TIGH: No, it's not okay.
像是让我抛弃岗位
I feel like I'm abandoning my post.
现在是离开的时间了 索尔
It's time to pack it in, Saul. You know it.
我们有一半以上的舰员已经在地面上了
More than half the crew is down there on the ground already.
我们已经很难让一个满编小队起飞执行训练任务了
We can barely put a squadron in the air to train,
能驾驶大点飞船的人更少
much less fly a decent cap.
我们也没啥事要做了
We're not really doing too much up here anymore.
你还待在这?
Well, you're staying.
这儿总需要有人打点
Yeah, well, someone has to take care of the lighthouse.
那我也和你一起待这
Then I'll stay and take care of it with you.
很感谢你这么说
I appreciate that.
但你知道这只需要我们中的一个
But you know there's only one person per lighthouse.
我们都知道赛昂人可能还会出现
We both know the Cylons could still show up.
什么事都有可能发生
Anything's possible.
现在我们绕这轨道飞行的天数
But we've been orbiting New Caprica
比被赛隆人追着跑的日子还多
longer than we ran after the attack.
我想他们不会再来了
I don't think they're coming back anymore.
上校
Colonel,
祝好运
good luck.
如果她给你惹麻烦
If she gives you too much trouble,
就找一个更年轻的
find yourself a younger one.
注意 注意
WOMAN:Attention. Attention.
请捐赠剩余的衣物
Please donate any available clothing remnants,
到新卡布里卡洛克门前
to HTV's New Caprica LOK outlet.
大小和多少不限 您的捐助
Any and all sizes are needed, and your contribution
将帮助我们的孩子和老人
will help our children and elderly.
嗨 看到山姆了嘛
Hey, have you seen Sam?
在那边赛金字塔吧
I think he's over there playing pyramid.
谢了
Thanks.
把她
Set her up.
山姆 你这白痴
Sam, you idiot!
我到处找你呢
I have been looking for you everywhere!
你到底在想什么?
What the hell are you thinking?
似乎我有麻烦了
Looks like I'm in trouble.
科特尔医生在  你病了
Doc Cottle is here. You're sick.
你应该躺床上
You are supposed to be in bed.
我宁愿在这里完蛋也不想整天躺在床上
I would rather work this out of my system right here than lie in bed all day.
山姆 来啊
Sam, come on.
来啊
Come on.
没办法
Duty calls.
你得强硬点
PLAYER 1: Hey, you gotta be tough.
你去哪 安德斯?
PLAYER 2: Where you going, Anders?
明天老时间 接着来
Tomorrow, man. Same time, same score.
再找个人来
PLAYER 2: Send us another player then.
真不敢相信我嫁给个白痴  你还好吗?
I can't believe I married a moron. Are you okay?
还行
I'm fine.
没事
快 快
PLAYER 3: Let's go! Let's go!
啊
Ah.
我就回来 好吗
STARBUCK: I'll be right back, okay?
医生 等等
Hey, Doc, wait.
怎么样
So?
肺里有积水
There's fluid in the lungs.
恐怕是肺炎
It's probably pneumonia.
那就给他点抗生素
So give him something.
我也想
I'd love to.
可我们已经有几个月没有抗生素可用了
I've been out of antibiotics for months.
难道就这样了?
So what, that's it?
我还有很多病人要看
I have a lot of patients to see,
他很年轻也很壮实
but he's young and he's strong.
所以 让他好好休息 不要受凉
So, make him rest, keep him warm
运气好的话 他会好起来的
and with a little luck, he'll make it.
妈的
Son of a bitch.
请安静
TYROL: Please, just calm down.
大家听我说
Everybody listen, just for a second.
请安静
Please. Please. Be quiet!
都他妈给我闭嘴
Hey! Shut the frak up!
当你们选我做联合会主席时
When you elected me union President,
我保证我会让大家有活可干
I promised I would keep us working.
让每个人有钱可赚 最重要的是
Keep benefits flowing, but most of all,
让这个城市能够撑下去    上校
keep this city alive... Colonel!
你好
Hey!
我保证过让大家继续工作
TYROL: I promised we would stay on the job.
哇 看看你
TIGH: Wow, look at you.
你好
Hi.
很高兴在见到你们
Oh, I'm so glad you guys are here.
我也是
Me, too.
这真令人吃惊
It's pretty, pretty exciting.
是啊 穿旧了
Yeah, that wears off.
这里怎么了?
So what's going on here?
拜波尔塔总统所赐
President Baltar.
男女老幼都得靠我们…
TYROL: Men, women and children are dependent on our...
长官 安德斯病得很重
Sir, Anders is really sick.
科特尔医生推脱说...
Doc Cottle's giving me the runaround.
没有抗生素可开了
Says there's no antibiotics.
真是胡扯
It's a load of crap.
你就帮帮我吧
Anything you can do to help me cut through the red tape?
你该和阿波罗联系一下
You should give Apollo a call.
帕伽索斯上有备用药品
Pegasus is sitting on the backup meds.
他应该会给你一点
He'd spring some for you.
我很怀疑
Yeah, I doubt that.
已经过了很久了
That was a long time ago.
人会变的
People change.
健康福利 配给 公平薪酬…
TYROL: Health benefits, rations and fair compensation.
是的 我们身负重任
Yes, we have a vital responsibility.
好吧
Okay.
当你们意识到
There comes a time when you realize
那些你们用血汗和泪水建造的引擎
that the engine you've built with your blood and your sweat
正被不正当的使用着
and your tears is being used for something so foul,
被糟蹋着…
so perverted
这让你们心痛
that it makes you sick in your heart.
你们该把用在机器上的热情
And it's then that you must throw your body on the gears
用来制止这样的事情
and on the levers and on the machine itself and make it stop.
我们要让操作
And we have to show the people who run it,
和控制一切的人知道 只要我们是自由的
the people who control it, that unless we're free,
那些机器就不会运作下去
that machine will be prevented from working at all!
罢工 罢工！
ALL:Strike! Strike! Strike! Strike!
大家都懂了吗?
ROSLIN: Okay, everybody have that so far?
是的
CHILDREN: Yeah.
很好 你听
Good, you're listening.
总统有难了
Think the President has a bit of a problem on his hands.
大家看一下第10章
I also want you to look at Chapter 10,
十二殖民星的历史
it's the history of the 12 Colonies.
真的很有意思
It's really interesting.
那也是总统自己的问题
The President's problems are not our problems, right?
没错
MAYA: That's right.
大家今天的作业就是那些问题
Our problems are homework for everyone tonight.
现在 有些人要留下来
Now some of you are going to stay and help me
准备那个艺术演出
with the art project for the presentation.
没事的人 你们的父母来了
Everyone else, your parents are here.
可以走了
Get your stuff, let's go! Go on, get out of here!
再见   干得不错
MAYA: Bye, bye. ROSLIN: Good job!
很好 再见 谢谢
Yeah, okay. Bye, honey, thanks.
很好 很好
Good job. Good job.
我又好了…
CHILD: I finished again...
真棒!
WOMAN: That's wonderful.
谢谢各位父母
ROSLIN: Thank you, parents!
我说
You know what?
你为何不去照看一下你的孩子呢? 这里有我在
Why don't you take the baby and go on, okay? I'll finish up here.
你确定?    是的
You sure? Yes.
没错 去吧
Yes, go ahead.
一个摇头娃娃 我喜欢  你还没走?
A bubblehead. I love this. Are you staying?
好了 有工艺品的人 都拿到这儿来
Okay, everybody with an art project, bring it up here!
你好 伊西斯
Hello, Isis. Oh...
第7号能源线路
WOMAN:Section 7 power grid
暂时关闭检修
is temporarily shut down for repairs.
怎么了?
Hey, what's going on?
你的
It's for you.
是谁?
Who is it?
给你的
It's for you.
是谁?
Who is it?
好吧
Right.
你想要什么?
APOLLO: What do you want?
我需要帮助
I need a favor.
是吗?
Is that right?
我听说你有一些给飞行员备的抗生素
I hear that you're hoarding a bunch of antibiotics for the pilots.
你从哪听来的?
Where did you hear that?
安德斯病了 得了 李
Anders is sick. He has pneumonia, Lee.
很有可能会挺不过去
I think that he might die.
指挥官
Commander?
等下
Wait one...
中尉  是什么
Yeah, lieutenant. What is it?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
我在雷达上看到些东西
I'm picking up something on dradis.
雷达 在这云层里怎么能看到东西?
Dradis? How can you see anything in that soup? I mean...
就是这个    什么?
There it is. What is it?
等等 那是什么?
Wait, what is that?
我的天
Oh, my Gods!
是一支赛昂舰队
It's a Cylon fleet.
他们找到我们了
They found us.
我们必须离开
APOLLO: We have to get out of here, sir.
我们不能就这样留下我们的人
We can't just leave all those people behind.
我们别无它法了
There's nothing we can do.
我们什么都做不了
It's taking us forever just to get to action stations over here.
我们没保持战斗队列 长官
We're in no shape for a fight, sir.
留下的人会被屠杀的
They'll be wiped out.
我们没得选择 我们必须立即离开
We don't have a choice. We need to get out of here, right now!
所有部门都进入战斗状态了
All decks finally report condition one, sir.
是否要让预警战机起飞?
Should we launch the alert fighters?
不
No.
我们准备跳跃 我们要离开
Begin jump prep. We're leaving.
但我们会回来的
But we'll be back.
开始准备
Start your prep.
总统先生!总统先生!
Mr. President! Mr. President!
为什么不敲门?    盖尤斯
Don't you knock? GAETA: Gaius!
盖尤斯    怎么了?
Gaius! Yeah, what is it?
赛昂舰队刚才跳跃到了轨道上
The Cylons just jumped into orbit
我们的舰队跳跃离开了
and the Fleet's jumped away.
审判日来临了
Judgment day.
我在找卡拉 色雷斯
I'm looking for Kara Thrace.
我是盖尤斯 波尔塔
I am Gaius Baltar,
殖民星总统
President of the Colonies.
我知道你是谁 盖尤斯
I know who you are, Gaius.
我知道得很清楚
I know very well.
只要你们不抵抗
As long as you offer no resistance,
你们就不会被攻击
you won't be harmed.
我怎么可以相信你们?
How do I know that?
你不知道
You don't.
你也没得选
You also don't have any choice.
你们怎么找到这的?
How did you find us?
意外收获而已
Oh, it was quite by accident, actually.
我们在距此一光年外的地方
We were over a light year away from here
侦测到核弹爆炸后…
when we detected the radiation signature
残余的辐射
of a nuclear detonation.
好吧
Very well.
我代表十二殖民星
On behalf of the people of the 12 Colonies,
向你们投降
I surrender.
你打算怎么办 上尉?
What do you want to do now, Captain?
就像以前那样
The same thing we always do.
和他们战斗到底
Fight them until we can't.